MUHAMMAD MATLOOB

+92-336-8740091 matloob514@gmail.com

Age: 25



Objective

As an experienced individual, I would like to devise captivating, fascinating, and unique practices of teaching that creates interest in the students. With the help of my cordial nature, I would like to build good rapport with students as well as with colleagues.

Education

NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY (NUST)

MS Biomedical Sciences (3.65/4.0)

UNIVERSITY OF GUJRAT

BS Biochemistry and Molecular Biology (3.05/4.0)

BOARD OF INTERMEDIATE AND SECONDARY EDUCATION

F.Sc (secured A Grade in Pre-Medical)

BOARD OF INTERMEDIATE AND SECONDRY EDUCATION

Matric (secured A+ Grade in Science-Bio)

Islamabad, Pakistan 2016-2019 Gujrat, Pakistan 2011-2015 Gujranwala, Pakistan 2009-2011 Gujranwala, Pakistan

2007-2009

Experience

ILM Group of Colleges (2019-Present)

Teaching Biology & Biochemistry to Intermediate and Bachelor level.

High Aim Foundation School (2018-2019)

Teacher of Science subjects in high section. Design and develop classroom assignments and programs.
Conduct Examination and Develop Report Cards. Arrange parents' teacher meeting.

Lecturer in Academy (2018-Present)

- Teaching Biology to College students.

Noor International (March-July 2018)

Working as Sale Executive for Company that deals in biomedical equipment and provide service.

Medical Device Development Centre (NUST) (Dec 2017-Feb 2018)

Internship in MDDC, first company in Pakistan to begin with the production of cardiac stents.

MS Final Year Dissertation (2017–2018)

- Title "Computational analysis for the prediction of potential inhibitors of lactate dehydrogenase enzyme of Enterococcus faecalis"
- Description -Modelled the protein structure of LDH enzyme by Modeller.
 - Validated the modelled structure by different bioinformatics tools.
 - Searched the libraries and literature for potential inhibitors.
 - Docked modelled protein with these ligand through AutoDock Vina
- Results -Docking result identified different potential inhibitors that could be used along with antibiotics to kill infections of enterococcus faecalis.

Academic Activities

Workshop on Flow cytometry-2017 Islamabad, Pakistan

I have attended a workshop conducted by Alpha Genomics (Pvt) Ltd, which is the organization working in life sciences research, on flow cytometer principles, applications and data analysis (14th Nov.2017).

INSN-2017 Islamabad, Pakistan

I have attended 3rd International nanomedicine Symposium on Nanotheranostics 'The Power of Nanomedicine' conducted by NILOP Islamabad on importance of nanomedicine in treatment of cancer (21st Nov. 2017).

ARTID-2017 Islamabad, Pakistan

I have attended a workshop on application of robotics technology for industrial development in Pakistan conducted by Robotics' Dept. NUST (10th Apr. 2017).

ICBBB-2016: Faisalabad, Pakistan.

I have attended the International conference of Biochemistry, Biotechnology and Biomaterials (Feb 22-24, 2016)

UOG HAYATIAN BOOK SOCIETY: Gujrat, Pakistan

Initiate society of university of Gujrat to support students in providing minor subjects books.

Core society member: 2013-2015.

- Project
- Computer Aided Drug Designing of pathogenic Bacteria 'Enterococcus Faecalis' that is 2nd most dangerous bacteria causing nosocomial and UTI infections.
- Publication
- Published a research paper on In-silico structural and functional characterization of hypothetical protein; A new therapeutically target for S. Pyrogenes in ICBBB (FEB 2016).
- Honors and Awards

MEMBER OF NATIONAL YOUTH ASSEMBLY (2017-PRESENT)

Membership No. 4129

ACADEMIC SCHOLARSHIP Islamabad, Pakistan

 Received full merit based scholarship from Punjab Educational Endowment Fund (2016-2018).

ACADEMIC SCHOLASHIP Gujrat, Pakistan

 Received full merit based scholarship from Punjab Educational Endowment Fund (2011-2015).

CHIEF MINISTER'S AWARD

- Received merit-based Laptop Award from Chief Minister Punjab (2011)
- Extracurricular Activities & Additional Skills
- Interpersonal Skills: adaptable and sustainable ,collaborative and focused
- Strength: stress management, positive thinking attitude, cooperative
- Soft skills: Microsoft office, operating systems and software installation
- Interests: Reading books and novels, Reading newspaper, Attending events and sessions, welfare works
- Problem solver, decision maker, honest, creative, assertive and accountable.
- Entrepreneurial worker: driven to succeed, able to motivate others and work in teams

Reference: Will be furnished on demand.